
/* template
var catquestion = {
	category: ,
	questionNum : ,
	question : '',
	answers: ['',
				 '',
				 '',
				 ''],
	correctAnswerIndex : 
};
*/

//************************************
// Begin Category 1, American Trivia
//************************************

var cat1question1 = {
	category: 1,
	questionNum : 1,
	question : 'In the year 1900 in the U.S. what were the most popular first names given to boy and girl babies?',
	answers: ['William and Elizabeth',
			 	'Joseph and Catherine',
			 	'John and Mary',
			 	'George and Anne'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 2
};

var cat1question2 = {
	category: 1,
	questionNum : 2,
	question : 'When did the Liberty Bell get its name?',
	answers: ['When it was made, in 1701',
				 'When it rang on July 4, 1776',
				 'In the 19th century, when it became a symbol of the abolition of slavery',
				 'None of the above'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 2
};

var cat1question3 = {
	category: 1,
	questionNum : 3,
	question : 'Which of the following items was owned by the fewest U.S. homes in 1990?',
	answers: ['home computer',
				 'compact disk player',
				 'cordless phone',
				 'dishwasher'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1 
};

var cat1question4 = {
	category : 1,
	questionNum : 4,
	question : 'Who is third behind Hank Aaron and Babe Ruth in major league career home runs?',
	answers: ['Reggie Jackson',
				 'Harmon Killebrew',
				 'Willie Mays',
				 'Frank Robinson'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 2 
};

var cat1question5 = {
	category: 1,
	questionNum : 5,
	question : 'What did the \'D\' in D-Day stand for?',
	answers: ['doom',
				 'day',
				 'Dwight (Eisenhower)',
				 'Dunkirk'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1 
};

var cat1question6 = {
	category : 1,
	questionNum : 6,
	question : 'The Brownie Box Camera introduced by Eastman Kodak in 1900 had a retail price of what?',
	answers: ['$1',
				 '$5',
				 '$10',
				 '$20'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 0
};

var cat1question7 = {
	category: 1,
	questionNum : 7,
	question : 'In J. Edgar Hoover, what did the J stand for?',
	answers: ['James',
				 'John',
				 'Joseph',
				 'Jerry'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat1question8 = {
	category: 1,
	questionNum : 8,
	question : 'Which character,in the Wizard of Oz,does Dorothy say she\'ll miss \'most of all\' when she leaves Oz?',
	answers: ['The Wizard',
				 'The Scarecrow',
				 'The Cowardly Lion',
				 'The Tin Man'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat1question9 = {
	category: 1,
	questionNum : 9,
	question : 'In the House of Representatives which state has more than one seat?',
	answers: ['Alaska',
				 'Hawaii',
				 'Vermont',
				 'Wyoming'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat1question10 = {
	category: 1,
	questionNum : 10,
	question : 'The Constitution protects citizens against "unreasonable searches and seizures" with which amendment?',
	answers: ['the fourth',
				 'the first',
				 'the ninth',
				 'the fourteenth'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 0
};

var cat1question11 = {
	category: 1,
	questionNum : 12,
	question : 'What is the most popular name for a dog in the U.S. according to  Harper\'s Index Book?',
	answers: ['Fluffy',
				 'Rover',
				 'Max',
				 'Spot'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat1question12 = {
	category: 1,
	questionNum : 12,
	question : 'Candlemass is known by what name in the United States?',
	answers: ['April Fool\'s Day',
				 'Halloween',
				 'Thanksgiving',
				 'Groundhog Day'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 3
};

//************************************
// Begin Category 2, Entertainment
//************************************

var cat2question1 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 1,
	question : 'Which actor starred in The Color of Money?',
	answers: ['Tom Berenger',
				 'Tom Cruise',
				 'Tom Hanks',
				 'Tom Stewart'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat2question2 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 2,
	question : 'The actor Mel Gibson was born where?',
	answers: ['Birmingham, England',
				 'Peekskill, New York ',
				 'Wagga Wagga Australia',
				 'Sydney, Australia'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat2question3 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 3,
	question : 'Which actor has the real name of Charles Carter?',
	answers: ['Chuck Norris',
				 'Charles Atlas',
				 'Charlton Heston',
				 'Jimmy Carter'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 2
};

var cat2question4 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 4,
	question : 'Monty Python\'s Flying Circus debuted on the BBC in what year?',
	answers: ['1959',
				 '1969',
				 '1979',
				 '1989'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat2question5 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 5,
	question : 'Whose autobiography was called Back In The Saddle Again?',
	answers: ['Gene Autry',
				 'Hopalong Cassidy',
				 'Tom Mix',
				 'Roy Rogers'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 0
};

var cat2question6 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 6,
	question : 'Goldie Hawn\'s  real first name is what?',
	answers: ['Godiva',
				 'Goldie',
				 'Gloria',
				 'Grace'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat2question7 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 7,
	question : 'What was Walt Disney\'s Mickey Mouse\'s original name?',
	answers: ['Manville',
				 'Melvin',
				 'Murgatroyd',
				 'Mortimer'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 3
};

var cat2question8 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 8,
	question : 'Which of the following entertainers was the highest paid for the two years 1988 and 1989?',
	answers: ['Bill Cosby',
				 'Michael Jackson',
				 'Madonna',
				 'Oprah Winfrey'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
}; 

var cat2question9 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 9,
	question : 'Which actress starred in the original Broadway production of Cabaret as Sally Bowles?',
	answers: ['Julie Andrews',
				 'Carol Channing',
				 'Jill Haworth',
				 'Liza Minnelli'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 3
};

var cat2question10 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 10,
	question : 'Which of the following men were not married to Ava Gardner?',
	answers: ['Richard Burton',
				 'Mickey Rooney',
				 'Frank Sinatra',
				 'Artie Shaw'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 0
};

var cat2question11 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 11,
	question : 'In the original Broadway production of The Unsinkable Molly Brown, who played the title role?',
	answers: ['Barbara Cook',
				 'Tammy Grimes ',
				 'Angela Lansbury',
				 'Debbie Reynolds'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat2question12 = {
	category : 2,
	questionNum : 12,
	question : 'When it closed in 1990, what play on Broadway had been performed the most times?',
	answers: ['A Chorus Line',
				 'Annie',
				 'Fiddler on the Roof',
				 'Hello Dolly'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 0
};

//************************************
// Begin Category 3, History
//************************************

var cat3question1 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 1,
	question : 'Which of the following explorers reached the North Pole?',
	answers: ['Roald Amundsen',
				 'Robert E. Peary',
				 'William Barents',
				 'Adam Sound'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat3question2 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 2,
	question : 'History students are taught about the "the fall of Constantinople" in 1453. to who did it fall?',
	answers: ['Christian crusaders',
				 'Mongol hordes',
				 'Ottoman Turks',
				 'Romans'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 2
};

var cat3question4 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 4,
	question : 'Catherine the Great ruled what country?',
	answers: ['England',
				 'France',
				 'Germany',
				 'Russia'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 3
};

var cat3question5 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 5,
	question : 'What was the next state after the original 13 to be admitted to the United States?',
	answers: ['Florida',
				 'Kentucky',
				 'Vermont',
				 'West Virginia'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 2
};

var cat3question6 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 6,
	question : 'The Creoles of today\'s New Orleans are descended from whom?',
	answers: ['French Canadians from Nova Scotia',
				 'French and Spanish settlers who lived in the city',
				 'refugees from the Crimean War',
				 'none of the above'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat3question7 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 7,
	question : 'George Washington is called the father of our country, but how many kids did Mr. Washington really have?',
	answers: ['0',
				 '1',
				 '3',
				 '7'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 0
};

var cat3question8 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 8,
	question : 'What were the first names of the famous explorers Lewis and Clark?',
	answers: ['Clark and Lewis',
				 'John and Lincoln',
				 'Benjamin and Samuel',
				 'Meriwether and William'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 3
};

var cat3question9 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 9,
	question : 'Where was the UN headquarters located prior to them moving to Manhattan\'s East Side?',
	answers: ['San Francisco',
				 'Long Island, New York',
				 'Geneva, Switzerland',
				 'Paris, France'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 1
};

var cat3question9 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 9,
	question : 'Which American commander said, "I have not yet begun to fight"?',
	answers: ['John Paul Jones',
				 'David Farragut',
				 'George Dewey',
				 'Oliver Hazard Perry'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 0
};

var cat3question9 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 9,
	question : 'John Brown of Civil War fame was which?',
	answers: ['an abolitionist',
				 'a slave',
				 'a slave-owner',
				 'none of the above'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 0 
};

var cat3question10 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 10,
	question : 'What frontier marshal was murdered in 1876 in Deadwood, South Dakota, by outlaw Jack McCall?',
	answers: ['Buffalo Bill Cody',
				 'Matt Dillon',
				 'Wild Bill Hickok',
				 'Bat Masterson'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 2
};

var cat3question11 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 11,
	question : 'In what year did Leonard Kristensen of Norway lead the first party to land on the mainland of Antarctica?',
	answers: ['1795',
				 '1845',
				 '1895',
				 '1945'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 2
};

var cat3question12 = {
	category : 3,
	questionNum : 12,
	question : 'At the time of the Declaration of Independence what was the approximate population of the United States?',
	answers: ['20,000',
				 '200,000',
				 '2,000,000',
				 '20,000,000'],
	correctAnswerIndex : 2
};

/* template
var catquestion = {
	category : ,
	questionNum : ,
	question : '',
	answers: ['',
				 '',
				 '',
				 ''],
	correctAnswerIndex : 
};
*/

//************************************
// Begin Category 4, Literature
//************************************
